SYED OMAIR HASAN

Karachi, Pakistan || engr.omair@hotmail.com || +92-332-2353312 https://pk.linkedin.com/in/syedomairhasan



July 28, 1992 | Pakistani | Male | Single



BMS ENGINEER

Technically sophisticated and solution-oriented BMS professional with excellent communication & inter personal skills having 3 years' experience in hardware and implementation, possessing good knowledge in building automation. Troubleshooting hardware and circuit problems and installation/assembling of all components, circuits and other applications related to BMS.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

• Digital Electronics and Instrument Design • Field Engineering • Project Planning and Supervision • Preventive and Corrective Maintenance • Problem Resolution • Process Improvement • Control & Instrumentation Component • Communication • Johnson Controls Metasys Mai • Honeywell EBI • Siemens Desigo Insight 14.1

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

DOLMEN REAL ESTATE MANAGEMENT PVT LTD, Karachi, Pakistan

Jun 2018 – Present

SYSTEM ENGINEER

- Play a key role as a System Engineer and hold the credit for implementing preventive maintenance of BMS DDC controllers and other field devices.
- Formulate, update, and retain snag and asset lists of pending work and equipments installed for contractors, attend complains regarding BMS, and resolve control panels issues in a timely manner.
- Display high analytical potential to plan, organize and expedite training sessions for building up the learning environments towards quality enhancement.
- Function in close collaboration with vendors and other teams and integrate various tasks while following follow health, safety and environmental requirements on the site.

IMPERIAL DEVELOPERS & BUILDERS PVT LTD, Karachi, Pakistan

Dec 2016 – May 2018

JUNIOR BMS ENGINEER

- Played an integral role in assessing control configuration tools, including Johnson control system, planning field point in graphics generation tools, and troubleshooting control panels and IBMS by Johnson Control system.
- Efficiently supervised and organized 30 floor building from control command center as well as operated LCP (lighting control panel) and BMS system to control HVAC equipment, electrical lightings / fire alarm system, and plumbing system.
- Examined quality of the equipment and system and delivered project in a timely manner and as per design.

IMPERIAL DEVELOPERS & BUILDERS PVT. LTD, Karachi, Pakistan BMS INTERNEE

Sep - Nov 2016

WIS INTERNEE

- Acted as an Intern and gained hands-on experience in the electronics engineering field.
- Directed contractors and vendors associated with the project, streamlined operations of field work activities, and created project status reports and snag list of pending work for contractors.

FIELDWAY TECHNOLOGIES, Karachi, Pakistan

Jun 2014 — Jun 2016

TECHNOLOGY CONSULTANT

- Served as a Technology Consultant and headed the responsibility for implementing and configuring CA applications.
- Integrated client nodes with domain and enterprise servers and transferred knowledge to stakeholders.

SYED OMAIR HASAN PAGE | 2

KEY PROJECTS

Implemented Enterprise I.T. Monitoring Solution (CA Spectrum and CA UIM) for Access Bank PLC (Nigeria on Site)
Implemented CA Client Automation for Access Bank PLC Subsidiaries (Nigeria)

PLC Based bottle filling and capping unit with volume detection (Final Year Project)

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Electronics Engineering, Sir Syed University of Engineering and Technology, 2015

HSC - Pre-Engineering, D.J. Sindh Govt. Science College, 2010

SSC - Matriculation, The Crescent Academy, 2008

PROFESSIONAL COURSES

PIC Programming Course, Technomen, 2013

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIP

Member, Pakistan Engineering Council (PEC)

REFERENCES

Will be furnished upon request